<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Age of Sail Home Page</title>
<link>http://students.webdev.emrjackson.com/c111/harmon/age_of_sail/ship_types.html</link>
<description>There are many different types of ships and tactics used during the age of 
sail era. So I will be mainly covering the ships, tactics and terms used from the mid 18th 
to early 19th century. However, many of the tactics and terms used during this time period 
are still in use today.</description>

<item>
<title>Ship Types</title>
<link>http://students.webdev.emrjackson.com/c111/harmon/age_of_sail/ship_types.html</link>
<author>alexander.harmon1814@email.cerrocoso.edu (Alexander Harmon)</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 12:00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>The Ship Rating System is a system at which the mighty British navy used to classify 
ships by the amount of cannons that are on the ship. Each nation had its own rating system but they 
were mostly all very similar to each other on how they ranked a ship. For this website I will be using 
the british rating system.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Ship Roles</title>
<link>http://students.webdev.emrjackson.com/c111/harmon/age_of_sail/ship_roles.html</link>
<author>alexander.harmon1814@email.cerrocoso.edu (Alexander Harmon)</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 12:00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>Every ship in the navy had a special role that it needed to do in order best serve its 
					strengths and weaknesses. Generally new captains were placed on small unrated ships in order 
					to gain experience before they moved up to commanding Frigates and only the top of the top 
					were to captain the massive Ship of the lines (SoL)</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Naval Tactics</title>
<link>http://students.webdev.emrjackson.com/c111/harmon/age_of_sail/naval_tactics.html</link>
<author>alexander.harmon1814@email.cerrocoso.edu (Alexander Harmon)</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 12:00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>Unlike many think, the battles during the age of sail era were won by making the enemy unable 
to fight by either demasting their ship or having the crew surrender. There were a few reasons for this but 
for one, these ships were mainly made out of wood so actually sinking a warship made to float was no easy task, 
wood floats after all. So instead making the crew surrender by either demasting or out maneuvering and gunning 
the enemy was simply easier to achieve.

However, there is another reason in which i talked about it briefly already in the ship roles page. Capturing 
enemy ships was one of the most important thing for a captain to do. Of course surviving and not getting 
captured was also very important. Capturing a ship would not only give a captain more favor with the admirality 
but also bring him, his crew and his country wealth. It was not that rare for ships to be captured renamed and 
refitted only for them to fight the enemy and be recaptured by the enemy.</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>